# TANUMAY MISRA () Featured

Senior analyst data science seeking roles in Application Development,Requirement Gathering,Requirement Analysis,Debugging,Bug Fixing,Coding,Testing,Client Management,Python,pyspark,MySql, Machine learning, NLP, Deep learning



Current Designation: Senior Analyst data science Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 3 Month(s)

Current Company: Infosys Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E.
Pref. Location: Kolkata,Bengaluru / Bangalore [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Python, MySql, Machine Learning, Data Mining, Natural Language Processing, Information Retrieval, Artificial

Intelligence, Neural Networks, Data Analytics, Time Series Analysis

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 16-Jan-21 Last Modified: 16-Jan-21

### **Summary**

Result oriented professional with 5+ years experience in software development. Worked on different type of neural network like CNN, RNN, GRU, LSTM using tensorflow and keras.

? Worked on Boosting algorithm like Adaboost, Xgboost, Light Gradient Boosting etc.

Worked on Natural Language Processing (NLTK, Spacy)

Worked on creating enterprise-based inference engine for quick solving of domain specific query

in a automated way (Sk-Learn, NLTK, Spacy)

Worked on data analytics and visualisation techniques

Worked to build different statistical models for data analysis. Extensively worked on time series forecasting

# **Work Experience**

**Infosys** as Senior Analyst data science Jun 2020 to Till Date

working as a data scientist

**HCL Technologies** as Technical Staff Member

Feb 2018 to Jun 2020

working to develop product based on NLP, ML and data science

Wipro technologies as Project Engineer

Oct 2015 to Feb 2018

Worked for number of projects based on machine learning, deep learning and computer vision

### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Haldia Institute of Technology (HIT) in 2015

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Python			
MySQL			
scikit-learn			
TensorFlow			
Keras			
OPENCV			
Pyspark			0 Year(s) 3 Month(s)
NLTK			
spaCy			
Pandas			
MATPLOTLIB			
Seaborn			
Pymysql			
NUMPY			

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Bengali				

## **Projects**

Project Title: Time Series Forecasting For Predicting Sales

Client: Carrier

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jun 2020 - Dec 2020 Project Location: Bengalore Onsite / Offsite

Role: Sr. Programmer Team Size: 4

Role Description: working on time series forecasting by using AWS forecast tool and statistical models

Project Details: Sales prediction based on time series analysis and statistical analysis

#### **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time